MAKSYM TSYBULSKYI

Sacramento, CA 95843 · 916-578-86-78 tomahawksmail@gmail · LinkedIn Profile · GitHub · WebSite

SUMMARY

I am an engineer with over 17 years of experience in IT. In total more than 12 years held the position of head of the IT department. My main qualities are self-management, responsibility and time-management. I always try to work for the result. I have completed a DevOps engineering course and I want to find a new job. I am always happy to learn something new and share my knowledge among my colleagues.

SKILLS

Ubuntu, Debian, Amazon Linux - Linux:

- MS Windows Server: AD, DNS, GPO, SMB

- Networking: VLANs, TCP, UDP, HTTP(S), VPNs

Terraform - laaC:

MySQL (MariaDB), MS SQL Server - SQL:

- Scripts: Python3, Bash - Version Control: Git, GitHub Docker - Containers:

AWS, Vodafone - Clouds:

- CI/CD: Jenkins, GitHub actions

- Web server: NGINX, Apache

- Orchestration: Kubernetes, Docker Compose, Swarm

- Observability logging: **ELK Stack** - Observability Monitoring: Prometheus - Observability Visualisation: Grafana - Synchronization: Rsync

- Virtualization: VMware, VMWare, Vagrant, ProxMox

- Configuration/Automation: Ansible

EXPERIENCE

07/2023 - CURRENT TIME SENIOR SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

USKO INC · FULL-TIME USA, RANCHO CORDOVA

- Divided Services into virtual machines (ProxMox) and Docker Containers
- Maintenance, management and updating current IT Infrastructure
- Maintain and update IP Phones, clients PCs, Linux and Windows Servers
- Implemented ticket system
- Management MySQL DB
- Perform regular updates and upgrades
- Created GPOs and Firewall rules for maximum security
- Develop backups
- Use DevOps practices for automation, laaC
- Support the internal Wiki (up-to-date documentation for all configurations)
- Implemented Grafana and Prometheus for all Services
- Created own Web App as a single entry point for monitoring and logging
- Preparing IT infrastructure for launching furniture production (Created structured Shared folders for generating G-code, connected CNC machines to LAN)
- Created Ansible Playbooks for Automation
- Create and renew ssl certificates

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY SPECIALIST

MAGMA LINE INC · FULL-TIME **USA, SACRAMENTO**

- Maintenance IT infrastructure

- Maintenance WEB server

12/2012 - 03/2022

02/2023 - 07/2023

HEAD OF IT DEPARTMENT/ ARCHITECT

CLINIC OF SAINT CATHERINE · FULL-TIME UKRAINE, ODESA

- Created the entire infrastructure of the company (purchase and configuration of equipment)

- Maintenance, management and adaptation e-commerce website

- Prepared and partial transfer of services to the Cloud (AWS and Vodafone)
- Automation and optimization of processes using Python
- Maintain and backup of multiple databases (MySQL and MS SQL Server)
- Maintain Kubernetes Clusters with own internal web services
- Management department of 5 employees

05/2010 - 10/2012

HEAD OF IT DEPARTMENT

"VIRTUS" · FULL-TIME UKRAINE, ODESA

- Construction and maintenance of IT infrastructure of the enterprise
- Maintened and backup of multiple databases
- Created two websites for the company

01/2006 - 06/2010

CHIEF ENGINEER

SECURITY SYSTEMS INTEGRATOR

"AGENT-SB" · FULL-TIME UKRAINE, ODESA

- Design and installation of security systems
- Created the entire infrastructure of the company

EDUCATION

2000 – 2006
ODESSA NATIONAL TELECOMMUNICATIONS
ACADEMY BY O.S.POPOV
UKRAINE, ODESA

Evaluated in US Bachelor's Degree in Telecommunications, Information Communication Networks

COURSES & CERTIFICATES

02/2022 HILLEL IT school <u>DevOps</u>
01/2023 AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials
01/2022 TP-LINK CERTIFIED PARTNER
01/2023 Troubleshooting: Amazon API Gateway
07/2022 AWS Compute Services Overview

01/2023 AWS Networking Basics
12/2021 AWS TECHNICAL ESSENTIALS
01/2023 AWS Networking Basics
01/2023 AWS Network Monitoring and Troubleshooting